[{"id": "5fd81b7dd0de9af39e9d4679", "question": "Who was the first woman to run for President of the U.S.?", "answer": "Victoria Woodhull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8e", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Merchant of Venice\", with whom does Portia fall in love?", "answer": "Bassanio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a15", "question": "What was the title of the 2003 Russell Crowe movie that was subtitled \"The Far Side of the World\"?", "answer": "Master and Commander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff5143bff04d658268c92e1", "question": "What coflict is sometimes called the African World War?", "answer": "Second Congo War\u00a0began in August 1998 and directly involved 9 African countries.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339724", "question": "What is Elton John's real name?", "answer": "Reginald Dwight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f716ea9e54d890926f6e0", "question": "In which country is the Troi-Rivieres bridge?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3c", "question": "What 2003 Samuel L. Jackson/Colin Farrell movie was based on a mid-1970's  TV show?", "answer": "S.W.A.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b918364247bf200fb888", "question": "What is the fear of flutes called?", "answer": "Aulophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0a", "question": "What year did Anna Nicole Smith die from a drug overdose?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4decd06d333868d34d71b", "question": "When did World War I officially end?", "answer": "November 11, 1918", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339057", "question": "Who wrote the \"Aeneid\"?", "answer": "Virgil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b38106d333868d34d6d8", "question": "Who introduced potatoes into Ireland?", "answer": "Sir Walter Raleigh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5de655fff89b9ec3da2d335c", "question": "What auto company made the \"flathead\" V8 engine, which was the first affordable mass market V8?", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7dabff048f679a45abfb", "question": "Algophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Pain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8fb", "question": "What is the leaf of a fern called?", "answer": "Frond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b777", "question": "Julia Child, known as \"The French Chef\", was born in what country?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078566bd51d85e222ab65e", "question": "Who said: \"I\u2019m the president of the United States, and I\u2019m not going to eat any more broccoli\"?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush (He once made a joke that the workers in the Office of Personnel Management would get merit pay \"in broccoli\").", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd9937e83c707845b217b", "question": "What is the name of the woman Mario is attempting to save from the giant ape in the original Donkey Kong?", "answer": "Pauline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28d", "question": "What is the fruit of the \"Ananas comosus\"?", "answer": "A pineapple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a813", "question": "The city of Liverpool, England is served by an airport named for what man?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f8e7fe83fe1f2a824c30", "question": "On 1 April 1946, which disaster struck Hawaii which people initially thought was a hoax?", "answer": "Tsunami -- The disaster killed 160 people and was dubbed the April Fools Tsunami because so many thought the warnings a hoax.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937eb5b08d98002fdd633ad", "question": "Which three family members released an album titled \"Priority\" in 1979?", "answer": "The Pointer Sisters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abde", "question": "What is the capital of Northern Mariana Islands?", "answer": "Saipan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26d", "question": "What is a nanominute?", "answer": "One-billionth of a minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0c", "question": "What was the name of the shipwrecked boat on \"Gilligan's Island\"?", "answer": "S.S. Minnow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab9c", "question": "The port of Piraeus is located in which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cd", "question": "What was the first man-made object to leave the Solar System?", "answer": "Voyager 1", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62e", "question": "How many planets in our Solar System have moons?", "answer": "6", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e80", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Short-Timers\" set?", "answer": "Vietnam War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd440e347d002c297e4ae", "question": "Which band was Rod Stewart a member of before going solo?", "answer": "Faces\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d96", "question": "Who replaced Stanley Kubrick on the western film \"One-Eyed Jacks\", making it the only film he ever directed?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c542", "question": "What plant does the Colorado beetle attack?", "answer": "Potato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc1", "question": "What onetime NBA Finals MVP was the last owner of the CBA before its 2001 bankruptcy?", "answer": "Isiah Thomas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91a", "question": "What animal always gives birth to same sex twins?", "answer": "Armadillo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a94720565ad31a57c800", "question": "What was the name of the outlaw gang in Tombstone, Arizona that was Wyatt Earp's arch enemy?", "answer": "Cochise County Cowboys", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597ddba577980686f722d177", "question": "What year was the first patent for a pencil sharpener applied for?", "answer": "1828", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c86b877e98cb977789e4", "question": "Where can you see the petroglyphs of Newspaper Rock?", "answer": "Petrified Forrest National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf5", "question": "What's the name of the Jolly Green Giant's sidekick?", "answer": "Little Green Sprout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc1277469bb8041d07a07c", "question": "Vampires are typically known for turning into which animal?", "answer": "Bat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d78", "question": "What movie features three tunnels named Tom, Dick, and Harry?", "answer": "The Great Escape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012188763c99d48cd169af4", "question": "What flavor is Cointreau?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b3", "question": "What was Tom Cruise\u2019s character\u2019s name in the \"Mission Impossible\" movie series?", "answer": "Ethan Hunt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b0", "question": "What is the name of the coffee shop the \"Friends\" gang frequents?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc0", "question": "Who met longtime best friend Gayle King in 1976?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f3057b85aa2bc17b61b2ad3", "question": "What Shakespearean play features the fictional character, Iago?", "answer": "Othello", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e80658de59ea584496feb0", "question": "The character Smike appears in which Dickens novel?", "answer": "Nicholas Nickleby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3a", "question": "In the song \"Zip-a-Dee-Doo-Dah\", what kind of animal sits on Uncle Remus' shoulder?", "answer": "A bluebird", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f1", "question": "In 1917, Finland declared its independence from what country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f0", "question": "Which continent is the home of the tsetse fly?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ea2ffe83fe1f2a824bee", "question": "Who built a private apartment near the top of a tower named for himself and entertained Thomas Edison in it?", "answer": "Gustave Eiffel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06e", "question": "What was the infamous pseudonym of William Bonney?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c845", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the sclera?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339422", "question": "Who played the role of Jade in the 2009 movie \"The Hangover\"?", "answer": "Heather Graham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adac", "question": "Who was Araminta Ross known as?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523f3b736d4be723796b57", "question": "Which event was Canada\u2019s anthem, \"O Canada\", originally commissioned for?", "answer": "The 1880 St. Jean-Baptiste Day ceremony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59068076ff9c0647b50a808c", "question": "At what age did Prince release his debut album \"For You\"?", "answer": "19", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd7367e83c707845b2172", "question": "Which NFL team's name was inspired by a famous writer?", "answer": "Baltimore Ravens (The name comes from the poem \"The Raven,\" written by Edgar Allan Poe who called Baltimore home.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd7947e83c707845b2173", "question": "What popular movie musical, directed by John Huston, was released in 1982?", "answer": "\"Annie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4e", "question": "What was the name of the first Sony-branded transistor radio?", "answer": "The TR-55", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab949d86faa38a764be50e", "question": "What company made the LFA?", "answer": "Lexus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b335", "question": "What brand of melty cheese was first introduced to the mass market in 1928?", "answer": "Velveeta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c96", "question": "In Charles Dickens' \"Oliver Twist\", what is the name of the man who trains boys to steal for him?", "answer": "Fagin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaba", "question": "What is the capital of Solomon Islands?", "answer": "Honiara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a145", "question": "What is the name of the Duke Boys' car?", "answer": "General Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde4a92c6c6b019850c9a77", "question": "What fruit did Native Americans use to treat arrow wounds and to dye clothes?", "answer": "Cranberries", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fbaefd00738315b1fb74e33", "question": "Which is the longest English word without a vowel?", "answer": "Nymphly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59068295ff9c0647b50a809e", "question": "On what streaming platform was Kanye West\u2019s \"The Life of Pablo\" album launched?", "answer": "Tidal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338968", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was arachnophobic?", "answer": "Little Miss Muffet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65650ae7e414034b5aec6", "question": "During the Renaissance, Rome had a major rivalry with which city?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1ef0d145fb2946670738b", "question": "\"The Champagne Of Bottled Beer\" has been which company's ad slogan?", "answer": "Miller Beer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd509000d154d7af00b8d7", "question": "Tom DeLonge, Mark Hoppus and Scott Raynor formed which band?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a673", "question": "Which two US states are separated by the Delaware Bay?", "answer": "Delaware and New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febabf47e83c707845b20e9", "question": "What species holds the Guinness World Record for heaviest insect?", "answer": "Goliath beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999c", "question": "What 60\u2019s TV series featured the three Bradley daughters, Betty Jo, Billie Jo, and Bobbie Jo?", "answer": "Petticoat Junction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c814", "question": "What element must be burned out of pig iron to make steel?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c37f6815febcc896f9277", "question": "What is the sixth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Virgo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d51", "question": "What is 007 enemy Dr. No's first name?", "answer": "Julius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c6", "question": "What vitamin is sometimes referred to as the \"sunshine vitamin\"?", "answer": "Vitamin D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339871", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", what is the White Rabbit constantly worried about?", "answer": "Being late", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1e", "question": "Which royal palace was damaged by fire in 1986?", "answer": "Hampton Court Palace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e38", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Mrs. Whatsit\"?", "answer": "A Wrinkle in Time", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6a", "question": "In what year did Cassius Clay win an Olympic gold medal for boxing in the light heavyweight division?", "answer": "1960", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9e", "question": "William de Tracy played a part in the murder of which \"chief overseer\"?", "answer": "Archbishop Thomas Becket", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef65ca6ce05a3942286e71", "question": "In \"Saved by the Bell\", the main characters create a band called what?", "answer": "Zack Attack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2f", "question": "How many players are there in a standard baseball team?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc8", "question": "Beavis and Butthead worked part-time where?", "answer": "Burger World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e7e106d333868d34d744", "question": "A purple stripe on a Roman tunic was a sign of what?", "answer": "Status", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d62", "question": "Who played the role of TV's C. J. Cegg?", "answer": "Allison Janney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523c9d736d4be723796b39", "question": "What are Canada\u2019s two official sports?", "answer": "Ice hockey and lacrosse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56e", "question": "What sport uses a \"pigskin\"?", "answer": "Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff1", "question": "Under what name is Thomas Lanier Williams better known?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b9", "question": "What is a calorie a unit of?", "answer": "Energy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6571aae7e414034b5aed6", "question": "Samuel Tilden, Grover Cleveland, Al Gore, and Hillary Clinton share what distinction among U.S. presidential candidates?", "answer": "They won the popular vote but lost the electoral college vote", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca48", "question": "What is an Aasvogel?", "answer": "A vulture", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b38", "question": "What Blue Collar Comedy Tour comedian is known for his routine concerning \"Tater Salad\"?", "answer": "Ron White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c3b49076251badbead0", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to graduate college?", "answer": "Lucy Hayes -- The wife of President Rutherford B. Hayes, she received her degree from Wesleyan Female College at the age of 18.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa34", "question": "What is the capital of Italy?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8d", "question": "In what year was nylon first synthesized?", "answer": "1935", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe527561bf59ab7d2e380f9", "question": "What is the largest number of children to be born in a single birth and survive?", "answer": "8", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42a", "question": "Which is known as the Red Planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3b0eff048f679a45ab31", "question": "Who invented the microscope?", "answer": "Zacharias Janssen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600241cf4be4723ccac2217d", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Winnie-the-Pooh\" books?", "answer": "A.A. Milne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b1b0e662d71a53650fd2", "question": "Where was the graveyard located where Lord Voldemort made his return?", "answer": "Little Hangleton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93cd86bd93ce3a4e5f6ad", "question": "What scientist discovered X-rays?", "answer": "Wilhelm R\u00f6ntgen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c50c", "question": "What playing card symbolizes death?", "answer": "Ace of spades", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb19", "question": "Who did Tony Romo replace in 2006 as the Dallas Cowboys starting quarterback?", "answer": "Drew Bledsoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b1", "question": "What year saw the release of \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ef", "question": "Who played Daniel LaRusso in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Ralph Macchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a790", "question": "What country lies on Israel\u2019s northern border?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec85e4ec223966ae8f880b", "question": "What is the name of the first videogame in the \"Warcraft\" series?", "answer": "\"Orcs & Humans\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f7", "question": "Who was the first Toronto Blue Jay player to lead the American league in home runs?", "answer": "Jesse Barfield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e972aebfabb9c85d8a962", "question": "What is often called the \"Greek Old Testament\"?", "answer": "The Septuagint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c343", "question": "What is the sound a camel makes called?", "answer": "Nuzzing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91c", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Point?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f8", "question": "What instrument is used to measure atmospheric pressure?", "answer": "Barometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b13", "question": "Who did Lionel Richie duet with on the 1981 #1 smash \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6013709c1381754895396383", "question": "Actor Earl Hindman always hid behind a fence in which '90s TV show?", "answer": "\"Home Improvement\", which aired from 1991 to 1999.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a58", "question": "What literary character comes from Villa Villekulla in Sweden?", "answer": "Pippi Longstocking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c223", "question": "Petroselinum crispum is the Latin name of which herb?", "answer": "Parsley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f78", "question": "What was Buddy Holly's backing band?", "answer": "The Crickets", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2911c9bff04efae6d754", "question": "In what 1967 film did Gene Hackman earn his first Oscar nomination?", "answer": "Bonnie and Clyde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339579", "question": "In A Christmas Carol what song is sung outside of Scrooge's office?", "answer": "God Rest Ye Merry Gentlemen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb6327e83c707845b2124", "question": "Which land mammal has the most teeth?", "answer": "Giant armadillo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b258", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with Searches and seizures?", "answer": "Fourth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b2", "question": "How many rings are there on a five-zone archery target?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbf", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Water Buffaloes\" fraternity?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87b", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Nathan Road\"?", "answer": "Hong Kong", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad60", "question": "The 2008 Summer Olympic Games were held in what city?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe938766bd93ce3a4e5f685", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 2009 for studies of the structure and function of the ribosome?", "answer": "Ada E. Yonath", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bae", "question": "What was the last name of the main family on the TV show \"3rd Rock From the Sun\"?", "answer": "Solomon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900a", "question": "In what Agatha Christie book does Hercule Poriot die?", "answer": "Curtain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab5370b8cce1e6fda704b", "question": "How can you tell if cranberries are ripe?", "answer": "They bounce like rubber balls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b301", "question": "In what city is the Schloss Cecilienhof, site of a historic 1945 conference?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe771daeec85e375820b301", "question": "Which U.S. state has a town named after a game show?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952e", "question": "What character did John Goodman play on Roseanne?", "answer": "Dan Conner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd4177e83c707845b2159", "question": "Which famous actor was offered the role of Neo in the film \"The Matrix\" but turned it down?", "answer": "Will Smith turned down the role of Neo to instead star in \"Wild Wild West\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b820", "question": "What flavors make up Neopolitan ice cream?", "answer": "Vanilla, chocolate and strawberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7ec5ab24f84e0b9f9ffe6", "question": "Which sport was invented by Dr. James Naismith in 1891?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a894", "question": "What city is home to the Oriental Pearl Tower?", "answer": "Shanghai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b615", "question": "In 1998 what company acquired the rights to ICQ?", "answer": "AOL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c6", "question": "In what country is the holy city of Mecca?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049f03cf93664eb10486b7", "question": "What US state is home to the \"One Shell Square\" skyscraper?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9a2cebfabb9c85d8a978", "question": "Which British Prime Minister died in 1965?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb9", "question": "What model was married to musician Nikki Sixx?", "answer": "Donna D'Errico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008df93f4f3bc4a292f862c", "question": "What does Passover commemorate?", "answer": "It commemorates how Moses safely led the Jews out of Egypt, where they had spent centuries living in slavery under the Pharaohs.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24c", "question": "What is considered the fifth sense?", "answer": "Touch", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff143a6b0ee8c595b6d39b4", "question": "What sci-fi author worked as a potato chip inspector?", "answer": "Octavia E. Butler", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339906", "question": "What elderly TV detective came out of retirement after his son, Hal, was killed?", "answer": "Barnaby Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913d", "question": "What was the Roman equivalent of the Greek god Poseidon?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0c", "question": "What quested-for treasure of Greek myth was the skin of the winged ram Chrysomallos?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82f", "question": "What traditional dish is served at Wimbledon?", "answer": "Strawberries and cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5fd", "question": "Which planet is known for its rings?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe12dd1e39efa6330e0fecf", "question": "In which US state is the largest county?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1eca1145fb29466707387", "question": "What does the Qantas airline name stand for?", "answer": "Queensland and Northern Territory Aerial Services", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae45", "question": "Of what nationality was the explorer Ponce de Leon?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5fc66ce05a3942286e47", "question": "The Kansas City Chiefs were originally known as what?", "answer": "The Dallas Texans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4b7eb8198b9a2b077964", "question": "Hugh Jackman is best known for playing which of the X-Men characters?", "answer": "Wolverine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd96", "question": "What British comedian refers to himself as an \"executive transvestite\"?", "answer": "Eddie Izzard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ed", "question": "What four US states begin with the letter \"A\"?", "answer": "Alabama, Alaska, Arizona and Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe522ae1bf59ab7d2e380e9", "question": "\"100% Squeezed Sunshine\" has been which company's ad slogan?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd53bec223966ae8f88ce", "question": "What type of business did Annie have that failed in \"Bridesmaids\"?", "answer": "Bakery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a03c6c0f9723ab15cb35", "question": "Who added \"under God\" to the Pledge of Allegiance?", "answer": "President Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e91", "question": "What detective novel begins with a dinner hosted by the mysteriously absent \"Mr. U. N. Owen\"?", "answer": "And Then There Were None", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a198", "question": "Which actor starred in both the 1961 and 1991 versions of the film \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Gregory Peck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1da", "question": "What organization in the US was co-founded by Ballington Booth?", "answer": "Volunteers of America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25ac4b63e5727cf5a4856", "question": "Who sang the title track to the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\"?", "answer": "Bryan Adams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd58ae347d002c297e4b7", "question": "What year did James Fenimore Cooper publish the novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\"?", "answer": "1826", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69b7220565ad31a57c75f", "question": "What English code breaker created a machine that helped to decrypt Nazi messages?", "answer": "Alan Turing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c911", "question": "Ouranophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Heaven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddb", "question": "Why was paradise paved over, according to Joni Mitchell's \"Big Yellow Taxi\"?", "answer": "To put up a parking lot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee9", "question": "Bullwinkle J. Moose hails from what fictional town?", "answer": "Frostbite Falls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c81afbde8045e48466cf", "question": "What are the tiny air sacs in the lungs called?", "answer": "Alveoli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc06", "question": "A crusiverbalist is someone who is skilled at what?", "answer": "The creation or solving of crosswords", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a093", "question": "What 1970's film came from a Pink Floyd tune?", "answer": "The Wall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf99", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, which two letters have the highest values?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a534", "question": "What US city is located on the shores of Puget Sound?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f1", "question": "In what movie does Steve Martin play the character of Navin Johnson?", "answer": "The Jerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c1", "question": "Which 1954 film won eight Oscars?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c993fbde8045e48466ef", "question": "What is a group of jelly fish called?", "answer": "A smack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96a2923c87fd04dd15e10", "question": "Who ordered the construction of the Palace of Versailles?", "answer": "King Louis XIII", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7c0a42b316f4693fb6798", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc3", "question": "In what year was David Bowie awarded the Grammy Lifetime Achievement Award?", "answer": "2006", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acba", "question": "What was the original Dutch name of New York City?", "answer": "New Amsterdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8c", "question": "What is the colorful stage name of singer Alecia Moore?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8cc", "question": "Burning potassium has what color flame?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d3", "question": "Where in Egypt is the Tomb of Tutankhamen?", "answer": "Valley of the Kings", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f443cee580c7f8fd1e57", "question": "What country has the largest tar pit?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b810e662d71a5365101c", "question": "Which political fiction novel won the 1947 Pulitzer prize?", "answer": "\"All the King's Men\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a75", "question": "For what 1997 film did Demi Moore shave her head?", "answer": "G.I. Jane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a398", "question": "What African country in which the entire population speaks the same language?", "answer": "Somalia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922c", "question": "What New York City night spot was the subject of a 1984 Richard Gere movie?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912c", "question": "Dale Arden, Princess Aura, and Dr. Hans Zarkov are characters from which classic American comic strip?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339881", "question": "In Star Wars, which actor voiced Darth Vader?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c704", "question": "What is the only chemical element whose name is only three letters long?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fc", "question": "According to Toucan Sam, what should you always follow to find Froot Loops?", "answer": "Your nose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f4a5cee580c7f8fd1e59", "question": "What was the name of the commission that investigated the assassination of John F. Kennedy?", "answer": "Warren Commission", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c7", "question": "The resort city of Aspen is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b801", "question": "How old is a Jewish boy who has a bar mitzvah?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea33deff048f679a45aaf1", "question": "Nikola Tesla started his career working for which later rival?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9a", "question": "In what year did the Pillsbury doughboy first appear on TV?", "answer": "1965", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a61902ebb971c1417fb88", "question": "How many hurdles are there in a 400 metres hurdle race?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad06", "question": "What was banned in the US under the terms of the 18th Amendment?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990f939fa5fdd6dd25324f5", "question": "What film did John Wayne win his only Oscar for?", "answer": "True Grit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93616ce05a3942286e8d", "question": "NFL footballs are made out of which material?", "answer": "Cowhide", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f4cffa5fdd6dd25324e6", "question": "Central African Republic shares its northern border with mostly which country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb4e77e83c707845b211c", "question": "What are the two species of coffee plants used to make coffee?", "answer": "Arabica and Robusta", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a24c9d816e292245c14", "question": "Who painted \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Salvador Dal\u00ed -- \"The Persistence of Memory,\" aka \"The Melting Watches,\" is one of Dali's most recognizable works.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cb70c85f96e155acab35d2d", "question": "Which country suffered the most casualties in World War II?", "answer": "Soviet Union", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd87", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Kumonga?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4a4349076251badbeab2", "question": "What holiday commemorates the day the last slaves were freed in Texas?", "answer": "Juneteenth -- It commemorates the day (June 19, 1865) that slaves in Galveston, Texas learned that they were free.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fc4efe83fe1f2a824c40", "question": "Which London department store was started by an American reatiler in 1909?", "answer": "Selfridges", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af98437aeb0982ee455954a", "question": "Which Japanese Act sang the intro to the cartoon series \"Teen Titans\"?", "answer": "Puffy AmiYumi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf0", "question": "Who is Penelope Pussycat's would-be seducer?", "answer": "Pepe Le Pew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e9", "question": "What color is a Northern Cardinal?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7b", "question": "Who was the first dog in space?", "answer": "Laika", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e34", "question": "Who is Rashida Jones' mother?", "answer": "Peggy Lipton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c339877e98cb97778992", "question": "What causes the gory-looking red tint of Antarctica\u2019s Blood Falls?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aedb", "question": "In which present-day country is the site of the battle of Waterloo?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b762", "question": "In soccer, how many yellow cards result in the ejection of a player from the game?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891d", "question": "Who created Iron Man?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f71", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Jim Douglas?", "answer": "Herbie, the Love Bug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95a97e55722f97b22684d0", "question": "What short film featured Mickey Mouse\u2019s first appearance?", "answer": "Plane Crazy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae16", "question": "Which European country invaded Libya in 1911?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30b", "question": "What character did Pamela Adlon play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Marcy Runkle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd4bc600d154d7af00b8ce", "question": "Which nu metal band released the songs \"My Way\" and \"Rollin'\"?", "answer": "Limp Bizkit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb08298cf631c2414a13b46", "question": "How many soccer players should each team typically hove on the field at the start of each match?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c193", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b3dfe662d71a53650fe5", "question": "Who is considered one of the last Classical composers?", "answer": "Franz Schubert", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c576", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is known as the Earth's twin?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af9858caeb0982ee455954e", "question": "Which physical force is the only one that is always attractive, never repulsive?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd82070d0de9af39e9d469d", "question": "How much did the New York City subway cost to ride when it opened in 1904?", "answer": "5 cents", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1d", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Douglas?", "answer": "Ashanti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b20", "question": "What is the name of the sarcastic housekeeper on \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Berta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339771", "question": "Which actor plays Tony Montana in Scarface?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339984", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's snowplowing business?", "answer": "Plow King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b290", "question": "Who was the first US president to die in office?", "answer": "William Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa1", "question": "What actress originated the role of Mame in the musical \"Mame\"?", "answer": "Angela Lansbury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f167aff7c52aae91cc07bc", "question": "What country borders the Republic of Guinea-Bissau to the south and east?", "answer": "Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f1affe83fe1f2a824c17", "question": "When was the first time that the city of Chicago dyed the famous Chicago River green in commemoration of St. Patrick's Day?", "answer": "1962", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a92", "question": "What is the station and platform number for the Hogwarts Express?", "answer": "King's Cross Station, Platform 9 3/4", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba497874c93a3298b2146", "question": "What is believed to have eventually killed Oliver Cromwell?", "answer": "Malaria and urinary/kidney infection", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37b", "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc0776ce05a3942286f09", "question": "Who played the judge in the 1997 film \"Rainmaker\"?", "answer": "Danny Glover", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef60f06ce05a3942286e4e", "question": "What did Clark Gable do four or more times a day?", "answer": "Shower", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a72", "question": "Who was the first American artist to have a painting on display in the Louvre?", "answer": "James Whistler", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cde06e347d002c297e4f7", "question": "Who wrote the classic science fiction novel \"Helliconia Summer\"?", "answer": "Brian W. Aldiss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bf", "question": "What does a coleopterist study?", "answer": "Beetles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b989", "question": "What is a \u2018half hunter\u2019?", "answer": "A pocket watch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa33", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Minnesota?", "answer": "Saint Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb64765ff7d326b622a95", "question": "What animal lives in a holt or couch?", "answer": "An otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5b8d6ce05a3942286e17", "question": "Frank Sinatra rewrote \"High Hopes\" for what president's campaign?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af2", "question": "What 1950's rock pioneer was portrayed by Lou Diamond Phillips in a 1987 film?", "answer": "Ritchie Valens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887f", "question": "What novel did Ian Fleming introduce James Bond in?", "answer": "Casino Royale", "category": "arts"}]